Guide to the Dick Thornburgh Papers, 1932- AIS.1998.30.14
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Campaign for U.S. Senate, 1991; XIV.
  - Issue Research, 8.
    - Research on Pennsylvania Issues, including Thornburgh's Gubernatorial Record
      - State asbestos regulations, February-November, 1985 (Box 927, Folder 21)
      - State funding for the Women, Infants and Children (WIC) program, January-June, 1986 (Box 927, Folder 22)
      - Possible criminal justice training initiative, October, 1981 (Box 927, Folder 23)
      - Mack Truck issue, summary, September 12, 1991 (Box 927, Folder 24)
      - Act 148 funding, memorandum from the Office of Children, Youth and Families, September, 1985 (Box 927, Folder 25)
      - Analysis of the Crime Victims Compensation Board regarding the Crime Victims Compensation Program, 1982-1984 (Box 927, Folder 26)
      - Analysis of the Crime Victims Compensation Board regarding the Crime Victims Compensation Program, 1982-1984 (Box 928, Folder 1)
      - Drug forfeiture law analyses, March, 1983 (Box 928, Folder 2)
      - Memorandum from Carnegie Mellon University to Claire Walker of the Office of Policy Development (OPD) regarding Title XX and subsidized day care, March, 1983 (Box 928, Folder 3)
      - Tax amnesty and its possible use in Pennsylvania, January-March, 1984 (Box 928, Folder 4)
      - Creating export companies in Pennsylvania, November, 1984 (Box 928, Folder 5)
      - Usury rates in Pennsylvania and their elimination, December, 1984 (Box 928, Folder 6)
      - Securities law and regulations in Pennsylvania, December, 1984 (Box 928, Folder 7)
      - Review of a proposal for a new financial intermediary for Pennsylvania using pension fund investments, November 13, 1981 (Box 928, Folder 8)
      - Economic and community development proposals made by Belden Daniels in his book, Innovations in Development Finance, 1979-1987 (Box 928, Folder 9)
      - Responses to anti-Thornburgh points in press conference with Senator Lloyd, 1979-1987 (Box 928, Folder 10)
      - Analysis of Congressman Ertel's economic development proposals, 1979-1987 (Box 928, Folder 11)
      - Analysis of Senator Lloyd's economic development proposals, 1979-1987 (Box 928, Folder 12)
      - Possible elements for the Pennsylvania "War on Drugs", 1979-1987 (Box 928, Folder 13)
      - Constitutionality of S.B. 1151, establishing mandatory prison terms for crimes against the elderly and youth, 1979-1987 (Box 928, Folder 14)
      - Private sector plant closings in 11 states, review and responses, June 10, 1985 (Box 928, Folder 15)
      - Pennsylvania Subchapter "S" provision corporations, June 6, 1985 (Box 928, Folder 16)
      - "An Analysis of the State Fire and Panic Act," prepared by the Office of Policy Development (OPD), 1979-1987 (Box 928, Folder 17)
      - "The Pennsylvania Housing Finance Agency: Its Role and Potential", 1979-1987 (Box 928, Folder 18)
      - "Strategies and Policy Options for Improving Housing in Pennsylvania", 1979-1987 (Box 928, Folder 19)
      - "Analysis of the Minnesota/Wisconsin Home Improvement Program", 1979-1987 (Box 928, Folder 20)
      - "Analysis of the North Dakota Beginning Farmer Loan Program Assistance Acts and the Georgia Family Farm Bond Program", 1979-1987 (Box 928, Folder 21)
      - Modifications to S.B. 664, to establish a Municipal Economic Development Agency to promote economic development and job creation, November, 1983 (Box 928, Folder 22)
      - Limitations on loan guarantees in the Family Farm Assistance Program, August, 1984 (Box 928, Folder 23)
      - "Labor Market Forecasting in Pennsylvania," prepared by the Office of Policy Development (OPD), 1979-1987 (Box 928, Folder 24)
      - "Review of the Work Sharing Concept for Use in Pennsylvania", 1979-1987 (Box 928, Folder 25)
      - Unemployment rate changes in Pennsylvania, June 26, 1981 (Box 928, Folder 26)
      - "An Analysis of the Primary Health Care Shortage in Pennsylvania", 1979-1987 (Box 928, Folder 27)
      - "Economies in Transition: Strategies for Coping with Plant Closings", March, 1982 (Box 928, Folder 28)
      - "Analysis of the Worksharing Concept and Feasibility of Use in Pennsylvania," prepared by the Office of Policy Development (OPD), December 13, 1982 (Box 928, Folder 29)
      - Proposed statewide Department of Public Works (DPW) transportation block grant, proposal and memorandum, December 6, 1982 (Box 928, Folder 30)
      - Cost Reduction I, II and III, Accomplishments and Actions, prepared by the Cost Reduction Study Team, November, 1979-April, 1982 (Box 928, Folder 31)
      - "Roots of Realignment: A Reinstatement of Republican Principles," Thornburgh's address to Yale University, November 7, 1985 (Box 928, Folder 32)
      - Department of Public Works (DPW) State/County Human Service Delivery Issues, September 24, 1984 (Box 928, Folder 33)
      - Human services zingers! and accomplishments, includes information regarding the Governor's address to the Harrisburg YMCA, April-July, 1986 (Box 928, Folder 34)
      - Human services funding and expenditures, 1983-1986 (Box 928, Folder 35)
      - Summaries of Mental Health/Mental Retardation (MH/MR) initiatives for the 1986-1987 budget, August 11, 1986 (Box 928, Folder 36)
      - Mental Health/mental retardation (MH/MR) program funding, 1985-1986 (Box 928, Folder 37)
      - Welfare fraud data, February 16, 1982 (Box 928, Folder 38)
      - ADFC error rates, questions and answers, 1979-1987 (Box 928, Folder 39)
      - Talking points on economic development, 1986-1987 (Box 928, Folder 40)
      - Business climate in Pennsylvania, August 19, 1982 (Box 929, Folder 1)
      - Employment zingers!, April 19, 1982 (Box 929, Folder 2)
      - Economic development funding, September 12, 1984 (Box 929, Folder 3)
      - Dun and Bradstreet Corporation, Data on new business incorporations and corporate locations in Pennsylvania, September 24, 1985 (Box 929, Folder 4)
      - Movement of Pennsylvania firms to the Sunbelt, May 27, 1982 (Box 929, Folder 5)
      - Economic development studies, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 6)
      - Top 50 Pennsylvania employers, contrasting March of 1978 with December of 1985, 1978-1985 (Box 929, Folder 7)
      - Alexander Grant and Co., Seventh Annual General Manufacturing Climates study, June 2, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 8)
      - Economic Revitalization Tax Credit (ERTC), October 16, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 9)
      - Commerce Department achievements (includes information regarding Ben Franklin Partnership), 1986 (Box 929, Folder 10)
      - Foreign investment in Pennsylvania, February-March, 1982 (Box 929, Folder 11)
      - Travel and tourism expenditures and Pennsylvania's resulting economic growth, 1986-1987 (Box 929, Folder 12)
      - Business opinions on the Pennsylvania economy, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 13)
      - Firms and jobs in specific industries, June-July, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 14)
      - Venture capital in Pennsylvania, April-October, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 15)
      - Securities reforms and facts on the Pennsylvania Security Commission's initiatives for economic development, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 16)
      - Exports and international trade, 1985-1986 (Box 929, Folder 17)
      - Stanford Research Institute (SRI): International, Economic Development Project to help enhance economic competitiveness in the Appalachian region, September-October, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 18)
      - Enterprise Zone program, 1983-1986 (Box 929, Folder 19)
      - Economic revitalization in Pennsylvania and Michigan, August 15, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 20)
      - Lindsey, Robert, "Long-term woes seen for California economy," New York Times, article regarding California's economic troubles, September 29, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 21)
      - Pennsylvania historic employment and unemployment data and growth rate, September 19, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 22)
      - Manufacturing employment in Pennsylvania, September 13, 1982 (Box 929, Folder 23)
      - Industry-specific employment trends, 1983-1986 (Box 929, Folder 24)
      - Positive economic data and Pennsylvania zingers!, February-November, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 25)
      - Monthly employment and unemployment data and Pennsylvania rankings, 1979-1987 (Box 929, Folder 26)
      - Annual Inc. magazine article entitled "Rate the States," regarding states' economies, October 1, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 27)
      - Personal income for states, May-August, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 28)
      - Pennsylvania Business Survey regarding employment, April-August, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 29)
      - National Planning Association (NPA) employment data, April 15, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 30)
      - Pennsylvania's economy, February-March, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 31)
      - "Summary of Day Care Changes in Pennsylvania", 1979-1987 (Box 929, Folder 32)
      - Walton, Mary, "Saying No to Welfare," The Philadelphia Inquirer article, February, 1988 (Box 929, Folder 33)
      - Rankings of employment and unemployment changes, 1983-1986 (Box 929, Folder 34)
      - Bureau of Economic Analysis (BEA) unemployment data, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 35)
      - Pennsylvania county unemployment data, August, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 36)
      - Dun and Bradstreet Corporation, data on new business incorporations for the first six months of 1986, September 12, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 37)
      - Workers Compensation facts, June 2, 1982 (Box 929, Folder 38)
      - Job service placements and zingers!, July 15, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 39)
      - Bridge construction data and statistics, June-August, 1982 (Box 929, Folder 40)
      - Highway spending and new jobs, March 19, 1982 (Box 929, Folder 41)
      - Transportation information and highway program, January-July, 1982 (Box 929, Folder 42)
      - Motor License Fund revenues, September 15, 1982 (Box 929, Folder 43)
      - Highway and bridge improvements, June-July, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 44)
      - Allocation of revenues from recent surpluses, 1983-1986 (Box 929, Folder 45)
      - State credit ratings, July-December, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 46)
      - General fund budget increases and expenditures, ca. 1982 (Box 929, Folder 47)
      - Average employment, total wages, taxable wages and average annual wage by major industry group, 1983-1986 (Box 929, Folder 48)
      - Federal funds and expenditures, June-July, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 49)
      - Tax increases and budget cuts in other states, 1986 (Box 929, Folder 50)
      - Pennsylvania state debt, June 18, 1982 (Box 929, Folder 51)
      - Fiscal management talking points, April-October, 1986 (Box 930, Folder 1)
      - Local property taxes, 1982 (Box 930, Folder 2)
      - Local school taxes, July, 1982 (Box 930, Folder 3)
      - Local school tax revenue increases, September-October, 1982 (Box 930, Folder 4)
      - Pennsylvania tax data and rankings, 1984-1986 (Box 930, Folder 5)
      - Local jurisdictions funding, August-November, 1986 (Box 930, Folder 6)
      - 1977 Steel Conference recommendations and Thornburgh's implementation, August, 1982 (Box 930, Folder 7)
      - Pennsylvania Industrial Technology Assessment Project, 1984-1985 (Box 930, Folder 8)
      - Federal aid to Pennsylvania, April-July, 1985 (Box 930, Folder 9)
      - Pennsylvania Economy League (PEL) "Study to Analyze State Expenditures and Implications of Spending Cuts" (during Thornburgh's governorship), March, 1991 (Box 930, Folder 10)
      - "Turning the Tide" program, implementation in Pennsylvania schools, 1985-1987 (Box 930, Folder 11)
      - Aging expenditures and zingers!, June, 1982 (Box 930, Folder 12)
      - Administration priorities, February-March, 1986 (Box 930, Folder 13)
      - "Background on Drug and Alcohol Prevention and Treatment Efforts in Pennsylvania", July 17, 1984 (Box 930, Folder 14)
      - Neighborhood Assistance Act tax credits for food and shelter, 1986-1987 (Box 930, Folder 15)
      - Pennsylvania's child day care system, May 27, 1986 (Box 930, Folder 16)
      - State aid to higher education, 1986-1987 (Box 930, Folder 17)
      - American Federation of Teachers (AFT) report on teacher salaries, November 14, 1986 (Box 930, Folder 18)
      - Expenditures and family and child welfare, 1985-1986 (Box 930, Folder 19)
      - "Fact sheet: early intervention programs in Pennsylvania" for handicapped preschool children, 1986 (Box 930, Folder 20)
      - "Pennsylvania's Initiatives to Assist the Needy", May 23, 1986 (Box 930, Folder 21)
      - Medical Assistance Program expenditures, December 19, 1983 (Box 930, Folder 22)
      - Education expenditures, 1982-1986 (Box 930, Folder 23)
      - Allocations of new state revenues in the Thornburgh and Shapp administrations, June 6, 1983 (Box 930, Folder 24)
      - Zingers! on state spending priorities, October 11, 1983 (Box 930, Folder 25)
      - Status of legislation in Pennsylvania House and Senate, 1984-1985 (Box 930, Folder 26)
      - Legislative achievements, 1979-1986 (Box 930, Folder 27)
      - Budget Office review and verification of zingers! and accomplishments, August-October, 1986 (Box 930, Folder 28)
      - Pennsylvania summaries of state initiatives, January, 1985-May, 1986 (Box 930, Folder 29)
      - Summary of initiatives in 1986-1987 Budget, August-September, 1986 (Box 930, Folder 30)
      - Pooled Local Government Loan Program, 1979-1986 (Box 930, Folder 31)
      - "Comparable Worth," analysis of equal pay for women and legislation (H.B. 1130), 1979-1987 (Box 930, Folder 32)
      - Local financial emergencies options, and possibility for development in Pennsylvania, October 1, 1982 (Box 930, Folder 33)
      - Property taxes and reform, 1978-1979 (Box 930, Folder 34)
      - "User's Manual to the Pennsylvania State Mandate Project", July, 1982 (Box 930, Folder 35)
      - Admissions testing program of the College Board and Pennsylvania's performance, May 22, 1985 (Box 930, Folder 36)
      - History of state appropriations for education, January 31, 1980 (Box 930, Folder 37)
      - Local school tax revenue increases, September-October, 1982 (Box 930, Folder 38)
      - National Education Association (NEA) report on education expenditures, February-October, 1984 (Box 931, Folder 1)
      - "Education of Exceptional Children," by Jack Weinstein, Chreighton Law Review, Vol. 12, No. 4, June, 1979 (Box 931, Folder 2)
      - Real growth in education subsidies, January 22, 1985 (Box 931, Folder 3)
      - Tax increases for selected Harrisburg area school districts, 1982 (Box 931, Folder 4)
      - National Education Association (NEA) statistics on per pupil expenditures, October 6, 1983 (Box 931, Folder 5)
      - National Education Association (NEA) "Ranking of the States", October 30, 1985 (Box 931, Folder 6)
      - Community colleges and technical institutions funding, 1979-1987 (Box 931, Folder 7)
      - "Jobs for America's Graduates," program design effort, 1983-1984 (Box 931, Folder 8)
      - Fact sheet and comparison of Pennsylvania's basic educational system to that of other states, 1984-1985 (Box 931, Folder 9)
      - "Turning the Tide" educational program publications, 1983-1985 (Box 931, Folder 10)
      - Governor's Commission on Higher Education, 1984-1985 (Box 931, Folder 11-12)
      - Role of Counties in policy setting and financing of human services, July, 1983 (Box 931, Folder 13)
      - "Health Occupations Training Policy for Pennsylvania", 1979-1987 (Box 931, Folder 14)
      - Expanded Home Care Services for the Elderly, 1979-1987 (Box 931, Folder 15)
      - Governor's Task Force on Special Needs Children, includes Final Report and Recommendations dated July, 1980, 1980-1983 (Box 931, Folder 16)
      - Prevention of fraud in government benefit programs, July 6, 1982 (Box 931, Folder 17)
      - Pension funds and housing, March-July, 1981 (Box 931, Folder 18)
      - Coordination and consolidation of funding programs for Paratransit Service, 1979-1987 (Box 931, Folder 19)
      - Background material on housing problems, 1979-1987 (Box 931, Folder 20)
      - Governor's meeting with the Housing Task Force, and presentation of its Final Report, June 8, 1983 (Box 931, Folder 21)
      - Creation of a Transportation Block Grant to Counties, January 10, 1983 (Box 931, Folder 22)
      - "An Analysis of the State's Role in Responding to Overcrowding and Physical Plant Deficiencies in Pennsylvania's County Jails," prepared by the Office of Policy Development, June 6, 1983 (Box 931, Folder 23)
      - Feasibility of coordinating funding for Mental Health/Mental Retardation (MH/MR) programs, June, 1984 (Box 931, Folder 24)
      - Concept Paper for a Family Support Services Program for Unemployed Workers by Harold Miller, May 5, 1983 (Box 931, Folder 25)
      - Legal services for the poor, May 8, 1981 (Box 931, Folder 26)
      - "Options for Preventing and Responding to Plant Closings in Pennsylvania", November, 1983-January, 1984 (Box 931, Folder 27)
      - Proposed new program and initiative regarding plant closings and economic adjustment, November, 1983-January, 1984 (Box 931, Folder 28)
      - Overview of state loan guarantee program, August 1, 1984 (Box 931, Folder 29)
      - Problems with mandatory plant closing legislation, October 1, 1984 (Box 931, Folder 30)
      - Changes in PIDA practices, including apparent increases in loans to small businesses, March 2, 1981 (Box 931, Folder 31)
      - Massachusetts Capital Resources Company, 1979-1987 (Box 931, Folder 32)
      - Analysis of the California Home Ownership Co-investment Program, July 27, 1981 (Box 931, Folder 33)
      - "Improving Pension Fund Investments in Pennsylvania", 1979-1987 (Box 931, Folder 34)
      - Pennsylvania Building Code Alliance's proposed Uniform Construction Regulatory System, June-August, 1981 (Box 931, Folder 35)
      - "The Opportunity Funding Corporation: Possible Initiatives Worthy of Consideration in Pennsylvania", 1979-1987 (Box 931, Folder 36)
      - New York state's Business Improvement District Law, 1979-1987 (Box 931, Folder 37)
      - "Massachusetts' Community Development Action Grant Program: Potential for Duplication in Pennsylvania", 1979-1987 (Box 931, Folder 38)
      - Analysis of the House Democratic Policy Committee Report on Rural Pennsylvania, April-May, 1983 (Box 931, Folder 39)
      - Massachusetts' Community Business Development System (MCBDS), April, 1983 (Box 931, Folder 40)
      - Analysis of S.B. 664, to create a Municipal Economic Development Agency, July, 1983 (Box 931, Folder 41)
      - Assessment of New Jersey's proposed "Infrastructure Bank", July 7, 1983 (Box 931, Folder 42)
      - Review of the Department of Education's Analysis of Options for Reducing Teacher Strikes in Pennsylvania, October-December, 1981 (Box 931, Folder 43)
      - Analysis of the report "Regional Changes in Manufacturing Productivity", January 13, 1982 (Box 931, Folder 44)
      - Minnesota's study of business licensing, summary and analysis, June 25, 1982 (Box 932, Folder 1)
      - Cash Flow Reserve Fund proposal, February 28, 1983 (Box 932, Folder 2)
      - Governor's meeting with the Housing Task Force, June 8, 1983 (Box 932, Folder 3)
      - House Democratic Caucus "Statement of Policy" and analysis, June 4, 1981 (Box 932, Folder 4)
      - "A Preliminary Investigation into False Identification Fraud in Commonwealth Programs", February 22, 1982 (Box 932, Folder 5)
      - "Comparison of Municipal Police Training in Pennsylvania and Other States", 1979-1987 (Box 932, Folder 6)
      - "Education and Training Assistance to District Attorneys", 1979-1987 (Box 932, Folder 7)
      - Prescription drug abuse, Prescription Abuse Data Synthesis (PADS) program, May, 1986 (Box 932, Folder 8)
      - Options for encouraging urban homesteading in Pennsylvania, January 25, 1982 (Box 932, Folder 9)
      - State Housing Task Force review of a Uniform Construction Regulatory System, June-December, 1981 (Box 932, Folder 10)
      - "Our Troubled Cities: Reality and Hope in the Urban Centers," report by the House Democratic Caucus, January 30, 1984 (Box 932, Folder 11)
      - Use of Pennsylvania Housing Finance Agency (PHFA) and Community Development (CD) housing funds for rehabilitation, August 31, 1982 (Box 932, Folder 12)
      - Home ownership co-investment programs, July-August, 1981 (Box 932, Folder 13)
      - "Mental Health Policy Formulation and Knowledge: Use at the National and State Levels" by Carnegie Mellon University School of Urban and Public Affairs (SUPA), June, 1983 (Box 932, Folder 14)
      - Mental Health Procedures Act (MHPA), 1979-1987 (Box 932, Folder 15)
      - Summary of therapies for mental illnesses, 1979-1987 (Box 932, Folder 16)
      - "Evaluation of the Mental Health Procedures Act (MHPA)" by Margaret Mary Pepe, 1979-1987 (Box 932, Folder 17)
      - Reorganization and consolidation of the Office of Vocational Rehabilitation (OVR) and the Bureau of Blindness and Visual Services (BVS), August 13, 1984 (Box 932, Folder 18)
      - Funding for the Office of Vocational Rehabilitation (OVR) and the Bureau of Blindness and Visual Services (BVS), November, 1983-March, 1984 (Box 932, Folder 19)
      - Public school expenditures for elementary and secondary education, July 29, 1983 (Box 932, Folder 20)
      - Budget, inflation and taxes, achievements and zingers!, February 11, 1982 (Box 932, Folder 21)
      - General information on state budget, July 31, 1980 (Box 932, Folder 22)
      - "Putting Pennsylvania's Budget Process into Perspective," by Raymond Pepe, 1979-1987 (Box 932, Folder 23)
      - "Comparable Worth," possible mitigating factors and amendments to legislation, 1979-1987 (Box 932, Folder 24)
      - "Women and Home-based Work," by Kathleen Christensen, Social Policy, Winter, 1985 (Box 932, Folder 25)
      - Causes of income differentials for minority populations, 1979-1987 (Box 932, Folder 26)
      - Hostile tender offers, July, 1984 (Box 932, Folder 27)
      - Analysis of Motor Vehicle Inspection (MVI) Effectiveness by the Office of Budget and Administration (OBA), January, 1981 (Box 932, Folder 28)
      - "The Role of Analysis in Government" by John Gibbons for the Office of Technology Assessment (OTA) for the U.S. Congress, April 9, 1981 (Box 932, Folder 29)
      - Administration position on local tax reform and meeting with the Pennsylvania Association of Township Supervisors, April 2, 1983 (Box 932, Folder 30)
      - "The Real Estate Tax and its Administration" prepared for the Business Council of Pennsylvania by the Pennsylvania Economic League (PEL), March, 1983 (Box 932, Folder 31)
      - Rebuttal to Commonwealth Association of Students' contentions regarding Thornburgh's record in higher education, December 17, 1982 (Box 932, Folder 32)
      - State support of higher education, February 3, 1984 (Box 932, Folder 33)
      - Oil legislation veto by Governor Thornburgh, October 12, 1984 (Box 932, Folder 34)
      - National Governors Association (NGA) meetings and sessions, 1983-1985 (Box 932, Folder 35)
      - Unemployment tax delinquency, 1987-1989 (Box 932, Folder 36)
      - "A Study of Act 75: The Impact of Welfare Reform", June, 1984 (Box 932, Folder 37)
      - Ben Franklin Partnership, 1983-1988 (Box 932, Folder 38)
      - Labor and Industry weekly report material, 1983-1986 (Box 932, Folder 39)
      - Labor and Industry accomplishments, 1979-1988 (Box 933, Folder 1)
      - "A Housing Policy for the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania: A Document Addressing Pennsylvania's Housing Needs for the 80s", ca. 1981 (Box 933, Folder 2)
      - "Medical Assistance Cost Containment," by the Department of Public Welfare, March, 1984 (Box 933, Folder 3)
      - Thornburgh tort reform initiative, September 23, 1986 (Box 933, Folder 4)
      - Recreation Improvement and Rehabilitation Act (RIRA), January, 1987 (Box 933, Folder 5)